{
    "id": "Economy_237",
    "claim": "WIKIpedIA WILL STOP FUNCTIONING THE WAY THEY ONLY GET TO JUNCLE USD DONATION DOLLARSUnited States. - The director of the 'Wikimedia Foundation 'responsible for managing the popular 'Wikipedia 'page, Jimmy Wales, revealed to the media that the cyber encyclopedia will close its doors next July after they only managed to raise USD dollars from the campaign donations they made to keep working. Jimmy pointed out that although the page officially recorded profits of more than USD million said money 'was only symbolic 'since not having direct sponsors the maintenance costs were getting higher and higher compared to their income, so they saw the need to launch the donation campaign in order not to close their doors: 'Wikipedia's success was indisputable because we always maintained an independent editorial line. We created the free encyclopedia to show the information as it is, without any political party or entrepreneur altering or censoring the data for their benefit. A website, however popular it may be, cannot remain without sponsors, of course receiving offers from powerful people who wanted to finance us but in exchange for censoring the content. If we agreed and sold the people would no longer be able to upload the reviews they wanted, the texts would be controlled by the sponsors and the page would lose its essence. We prefer (with all the pain of the world) to create the fundraising campaign, we thought netizens loved Wikipedia and were going to support us even if it was with USD meager dollar, it was really sad to realize that in  months we only managed to raise USD dollars. We feel betrayed because thanks to us thousands of students have been able to graduate as they did their jobs with what they found on our page ', he said. Wales points out that seeing their collection failed, they tried to contact the people who proposed to sponsor them again: 'We told them that we were willing to let them censor the information for their benefit but their pride was stronger and they decided to turn their backs on us. If we'd known people weren't gonna help us, we'd have sold out from the start. It is already a fact that the page will stop working, now students will have to search for their tasks in traditional encyclopedias (books) or manually write the texts they find on other pages since we were the only portal that allowed copy-paste without problems and that is why everyone consulted us ', he confessed. According to one expert, the reason the fundraiser failed is because the % of the public on the page are university students known as 'Studies ': 'Almost % of voters are university students who live a day, although they would like to donate many only have the exact money to survive in the week. The owners knew that and yet they decided to take risks, unfortunately the decision they made was not the best and that translates to the fact that they will now have to close the portal ', he said. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "www.elruinaversal.com",
    "date": "12/06/2017",
    "veracity": 0,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "We WILL STOP FUNCTIONING THE We thousands of students USD DONATION DOLLARSUnited thousands of students .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many students did Elruinaversal say they would stop FUNCTIONING?",
                    "answer": "USD DONATION DOLLARSUnited thousands"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many students donate to the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee?",
                    "score": 0.8129,
                    "answers": "We|nsubj\tWILL|aux\tWe|nmod\tof students|prep\tstudents|pobj\tUSD|compound\tof students|prep\tstudents|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "thousands of students The director of the 'Wikimedia Foundation 'responsible for managing the popular 'Wikipedia 'page, Jimmy Wales thousands of students The director of the 'Wikimedia Foundation 'responsible for managing the popular 'Wikipedia 'page, Jimmy Wales he The director of the 'Wikimedia Foundation 'responsible for managing the popular 'Wikipedia 'page, Jimmy Wales We to the media the people who proposed to sponsor them again its doors next the people who proposed to sponsor them again after WIKIpedIA only managed to the people who proposed to sponsor them again USD dollars from the campaign the people who proposed to sponsor them again WIKIpedIA the people who proposed to sponsor them again to keep working.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is the director of the 'Wikimedia Foundation'responsible for managing the popular 'Wikipedia 'page'?",
                    "answer": "Jimmy Wales"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many students did the director of the 'Wikimedia Foundation manage the popular 'Wikipedia page?",
                    "score": 0.7713,
                    "answers": "after WIKIpedIA only managed|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How much money did Jimmy Wales receive from the people who proposed to sponsor WIKIpedia?",
                    "score": 0.7595,
                    "answers": "USD|nmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Jimmy Wales manage to manage the'Wikimedia Foundation' page?",
                    "score": 0.7593,
                    "answers": "the popular ' Wikipedia ' page|dobj\tthe popular ' Wikipedia ' page|dobj\tthe popular ' Wikipedia ' page|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people did WIKIpedia sponsor again?",
                    "score": 0.7568,
                    "answers": "We to the media the people who proposed to sponsor them again its doors next the people who proposed to sponsor them again after WIKIpedIA only managed|nsubj\tWe to the media the people who proposed to sponsor them again its doors next the people who proposed to sponsor them again after WIKIpedIA only managed to the people who proposed to sponsor them again USD dollars from the campaign the people who proposed to sponsor them again WIKIpedIA the people who proposed to sponsor them again to keep working|ROOT\tthe people who proposed to sponsor them again USD dollars from the campaign the people who proposed to sponsor them again WIKIpedIA the people who proposed to sponsor them again to keep working|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Jimmy Wales?",
                    "score": 0.7339,
                    "answers": "www.elruinaversal.com reported on 12/06/2017 that thousands of students The director of the ' Wikimedia Foundation ' responsible for managing the popular ' Wikipedia ' page , Jimmy Wales thousands of students The director of the ' Wikimedia Foundation ' responsible for managing the popular ' Wikipedia ' page , Jimmy Wales he The director of the ' Wikimedia Foundation ' responsible for managing the popular ' Wikipedia ' page , Jimmy Wales|ROOT\tThe director of the ' Wikimedia Foundation ' responsible for managing the popular ' Wikipedia ' page , Jimmy Wales|appos\tThe director of the ' Wikimedia Foundation ' responsible for managing the popular ' Wikipedia ' page , Jimmy Wales|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The director of the 'Wikimedia Foundation 'responsible for managing the popular 'Wikipedia 'page, Jimmy Wales the people who proposed to sponsor them again out that although the popular 'Wikipedia 'page officially recorded profits of more than USD million We profits of more than USD million 'was only symbolic 'since not having direct sponsors our page maintenance costs were students higher and higher compared students income, so WIKIpedIA saw the need to launch the donation campaign in students not to close its doors : We WIKIpedIA success was indisputable because WIKIpedIA always maintained an independent editorial line.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did WIKIpedIA see the need to do?",
                    "answer": "to launch the donation campaign in students not to close its doors"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Why did WIKIpedia need to launch a donation campaign?",
                    "score": 0.8816,
                    "answers": "WIKIpedIA saw the need to launch the donation campaign in students not to close its doors|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How much money did WIKIpedia receive from students?",
                    "score": 0.8419,
                    "answers": "donation|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the director of the 'Wikimedia Foundation do to manage the 'Wikipedia' page?",
                    "score": 0.8264,
                    "answers": "responsible for managing the popular ' Wikipedia ' page|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Jimmy Wales do to help the students who wanted to sponsor the Wikipedia page?",
                    "score": 0.8221,
                    "answers": "The director of the ' Wikimedia Foundation ' responsible for managing the popular ' Wikipedia ' page , Jimmy Wales the people who proposed to sponsor them again|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the total profits of WIKIpedia in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.8163,
                    "answers": "that The director of the ' Wikimedia Foundation ' responsible for managing the popular ' Wikipedia ' page , Jimmy Wales the people who proposed to sponsor them again out that although the popular ' Wikipedia ' page officially recorded profits of more than USD million We profits of more than USD million ' was only symbolic ' since not having direct sponsors our page maintenance costs were students higher and higher compared students income , so WIKIpedIA saw the need to launch the donation campaign in students not to close its doors|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "WIKIpedIA created WIKIpedIA to one expert the information as the information is, without any political party or entrepreneur altering our page censoring the data for benefit.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did not alter the information on the WIKIpedIA page?",
                    "answer": "political party or entrepreneur"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who created WIKIpedia?",
                    "score": 0.8834,
                    "answers": "12/06/2017|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who created WIKIpedIA?",
                    "score": 0.8834,
                    "answers": "any political party or entrepreneur|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is WIKIpedIA?",
                    "score": 0.7996,
                    "answers": "www.elruinaversal.com|nsubj\ton 12/06/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tto one expert|prep\tone expert|pobj\tthe|det\tthe information as the information is|dobj\tas|mark\tthe|det\tthe information|nsubj\tas the information is|advcl\t,|punct\twithout any political party or entrepreneur altering our page censoring the data for benefit|prep\tany|det\tpolitical|amod\tor|cc\tentrepreneur|conj\tany political party or entrepreneur altering our page censoring the data for benefit|pcomp\tour|poss\tour page|dobj\tcensoring the data for benefit|advcl\tthe|det\tthe data|dobj\tfor benefit|prep\tbenefit|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is WIKIpedia?",
                    "score": 0.7996,
                    "answers": "www.elruinaversal.com reported on 12/06/2017 that WIKIpedIA created WIKIpedIA to one expert the information as the information is , without any political party or entrepreneur altering our page censoring the data for benefit|ROOT\tthat WIKIpedIA created WIKIpedIA to one expert the information as the information is , without any political party or entrepreneur altering our page censoring the data for benefit|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "A website Almost % of voters A website may be, cannot remain without sponsors, of course receiving offers from powerful people who wanted to finance WIKIpedIA but in exchange The owners the content.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of voters did elruinaversal.com report that a website could not remain without sponsors?",
                    "answer": "Almost"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does a website receive in exchange for a sponsor?",
                    "answer": "in exchange The owners the content"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many sponsors does WIKIpedia receive?",
                    "score": 0.8648,
                    "answers": "www.elruinaversal.com|nsubj\ton 12/06/2017|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of people wanted to finance WIKIpedIA?",
                    "score": 0.8603,
                    "answers": "Almost|advmod\tA website|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the percentage of people who wanted to finance WIKIpedia?",
                    "score": 0.7938,
                    "answers": "A website Almost % of voters|nsubj\tthat A website Almost % of voters A website may be , can not remain without sponsors , of course receiving offers from powerful people who wanted to finance WIKIpedIA but in exchange The owners the content|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is WIKIpedIA?",
                    "score": 0.7785,
                    "answers": "www.elruinaversal.com reported on 12/06/2017 that A website Almost % of voters A website may be , can not remain without sponsors , of course receiving offers from powerful people who wanted to finance WIKIpedIA but in exchange The owners the content|ROOT\tthat|mark\tvoters|pobj\tmay|aux\t,|punct\tcan|aux\tnot|neg\tsponsors ,|nsubj\t,|punct\tcourse|pobj\toffers|dobj\tpowerful|amod\twho|nsubj\tto|aux\tbut|cc\tin exchange|prep\texchange|pobj\tThe|det\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is WIKIpedia?",
                    "score": 0.7785,
                    "answers": "without sponsors , of course receiving offers from powerful people who wanted to finance WIKIpedIA but in exchange The owners the content|prep\tsponsors , of course receiving offers from powerful people who wanted to finance WIKIpedIA but in exchange The owners the content|pcomp\tfrom powerful people who wanted to finance WIKIpedIA|prep\tpowerful people who wanted to finance WIKIpedIA|pobj\twho wanted to finance WIKIpedIA|relcl\tto finance WIKIpedIA|xcomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The owners WIKIpedIA agreed and sold the people would no longer be able The owners upload the reviews the people wanted, the texts would be controlled by the sponsors and the page our page lose essence.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the owners of WIKIpedIA say about the page?",
                    "answer": "The owners WIKIpedIA agreed and sold the people would no longer be able The owners upload the reviews the people wanted, the texts would be controlled by the sponsors"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people did WIKIpedIA send reviews to?",
                    "score": 0.7701,
                    "answers": "the people|nsubj\tthe people|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many reviews did WIKIpedIA offer the people?",
                    "score": 0.7625,
                    "answers": "the reviews the people wanted|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the owners of WIKIpedia agree to do?",
                    "score": 0.7397,
                    "answers": "www.elruinaversal.com reported on 12/06/2017 that The owners WIKIpedIA agreed and sold the people would no longer be able|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did WIKIpedIA say about the claims made by the owners?",
                    "score": 0.7322,
                    "answers": "the texts|nsubjpass"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the owner of WIKIpedia say about it?",
                    "score": 0.7001,
                    "answers": "that The owners WIKIpedIA agreed and sold|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "WIKIpedIA prefer (with all the pain of the world) to create the donation campaign , WIKIpedIA thought netizens loved WIKIpedIA and were going to support WIKIpedIA even if support was with USD meager dollar, it was really sad to realize that in  months WIKIpedIA only managed to raise USD dollars.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did WIKIpedIA prefer to do?",
                    "answer": "create the donation campaign"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How much money did WIKIpedia raise in donations?",
                    "score": 0.8532,
                    "answers": "to realize that in   months WIKIpedIA only managed to raise USD dollars|xcomp\tthat in   months|dep\tWIKIpedIA only managed to raise USD dollars|ccomp\tto raise USD dollars|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did WIKIpedia say about the donation campaign?",
                    "score": 0.8316,
                    "answers": "that WIKIpedIA prefer ( with all the pain of the world ) to create the donation campaign|ccomp\t,|punct\twww.elruinaversal.com reported on 12/06/2017 that WIKIpedIA prefer ( with all the pain of the world ) to create the donation campaign , WIKIpedIA thought netizens loved WIKIpedIA and were going to support WIKIpedIA even if support was with USD meager dollar|ccomp\twere|aux\t,|punct\tit|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "We feel betrayed because thanks to us thousands of students have been able to graduate as they did their jobs with what they found on our page ', he said.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What have thousands of students been able to graduate from?",
                    "answer": "what they found on our page"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many graduate students have been able to graduate from the University of Florida?",
                    "score": 0.8129,
                    "answers": "that We feel betrayed because thanks to us thousands of students have been able to graduate as they did their jobs with what they found on our page|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Wales points out that seeing their collection failed, they tried to contact the people who proposed to sponsor them again: 'We told them that we were willing to let them censor the information for their benefit but their pride was stronger and they decided to turn their backs on us.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Why did they turn their back on us?",
                    "answer": "their pride was stronger"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Why did Wales turn their backs on us?",
                    "score": 0.7149,
                    "answers": "to turn their backs on us|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the Wales government say about the proposal to censor information?",
                    "score": 0.6792,
                    "answers": "to let them censor the information for their benefit|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Wales do to try to contact the people who proposed to sponsor them again?",
                    "score": 0.6665,
                    "answers": "www.elruinaversal.com reported on 12/06/2017 that Wales points out that seeing their collection failed , they tried to contact the people who proposed to sponsor them again : ' We told them that we were willing to let them censor the information for their benefit but their pride was stronger and they decided to turn their backs on us|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Why did they turn their back on us?",
                    "score": 0.643,
                    "answers": "seeing their collection failed|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did they do with the information they wanted to censor for their benefit?",
                    "score": 0.5756,
                    "answers": "them censor the information for their benefit|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "If we'd known people weren't gonna help us, we'd have sold out from the start.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did elruinaversal report that it had sold out?",
                    "answer": "12/06/2017"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people helped the store sell out from the start?",
                    "score": 0.8022,
                    "answers": ", we 'd have sold out from the start|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people were selling out from the beginning of 2017?",
                    "score": 0.8,
                    "answers": "na help us|xcomp\tfrom the start|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people would have sold out if they didn't know people?",
                    "score": 0.7843,
                    "answers": "that If we 'd known people were n't gon na help us|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the number of people that sold out from the start of the campaign?",
                    "score": 0.7747,
                    "answers": "n't|neg\tthe start|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It is already a fact that the page will stop working, now students will have to search for their tasks in traditional encyclopedias (books) or manually write the texts they find on other pages since we were the only portal that allowed copy-paste without problems and that is why everyone consulted us ', he confessed.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Why did students have to copy-paste?",
                    "answer": "everyone consulted us"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many pages did students have to search for their task in traditional encyclopedias or manually write the texts?",
                    "score": 0.8017,
                    "answers": "to search for their tasks in traditional encyclopedias ( books ) or manually write the texts they find on other pages since we were the only portal that allowed copy - paste without problems and that is why everyone consulted us|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the first website to allow copy-paste without problems?",
                    "score": 0.6647,
                    "answers": "working|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the only website that allowed copy-paste without problems?",
                    "score": 0.6339,
                    "answers": "the only portal that allowed copy - paste without problems|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of creating copy-paste?",
                    "score": 0.6303,
                    "answers": "for their tasks in traditional encyclopedias ( books )|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the problems with copy-paste?",
                    "score": 0.6209,
                    "answers": "problems|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "According to one expert, the reason the fundraiser failed is because the % of the public on the page are university students known as 'Studies ': 'Almost % of voters are university students who live a day, although they would like to donate many only have the exact money to survive in the week.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the % of the public on the Elruinaversal page that are university students known as?",
                    "answer": "'Studies"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of students want to donate money to the University of Florida?",
                    "score": 0.8266,
                    "answers": "that According to one expert , the reason the fundraiser failed is because the % of the public on the page are university students known as ' Studies ' : ' Almost % of voters are university students who live a day , although they would like to donate many only have the exact money to survive in the week|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the percentage of students who live a day that donate money?",
                    "score": 0.7352,
                    "answers": "to one expert|prep\tthe reason the fundraiser failed|nsubj\tthe fundraiser failed|relcl\tthe public on the page|pobj\ton the page|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The owners knew that and yet they decided to take risks, unfortunately the decision they made was not the best and that translates to the fact that they will now have to close the portal ', he said.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the owners of Elruinaversal have to do?",
                    "answer": "they will now have to close the portal"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Why did the owners decide to close the portal?",
                    "score": 0.7958,
                    "answers": "that The owners knew that and yet they decided to take risks , unfortunately the decision they made was not the best and that translates to the fact that they will now have to close the portal|ccomp\tthat they will now have to close the portal|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the website that closed the portal?",
                    "score": 0.5641,
                    "answers": "www.elruinaversal.com|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the owner of the website and the owners of it?",
                    "score": 0.5316,
                    "answers": "risks|dobj"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}